Benjamin Franklin Papers Part 14 -- Materials held at the University of Pennsylvania 1705-1788 Mss.B.F85inventory14
American Philosophical Society
- Correspondence (University of Pennsylvania), 1758-1788
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 July 22; A.L.S. 2p.; Hüllmandel, -----. Paris
    Requesting Dr. Franklin to grant an interview to a friend of his, who has made an important discovery in physics.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 July 24; A.L.S. 3p.; Stevenson, Mrs. Margaret. London
    News of mutual friends. Desires to see him once again before she dies.
    A.E. by Dr. Franklin. Noting her death on Jan. 1, 1783.
  - Appendix, 1782 July 29; A.L.S. 1p.; Hunter, James. Richmond, Va
    Enclosing a letter for Mrs. [Isabella] Strange, and apologizing profusely for troubling him.
  - Appendix, 1782 July; A.L.S. 1p.; Nogaret, François-Félix
    Acknowledging with every mark of gratitude and pleasure his gift of his medallion portrait.
  - Appendix, 1782 August 7; A.L.S. 2p.; Chaimleÿ, George. Brest
    Escaped from a British prison; asks for money to enable him to return to Boston; his uncle, Dr. Chaimleÿ, will repay it.
  - Appendix, 1782 August 8; A.L.S. 3p.; Bassi, Anton-Benedetto. Paris
    Two years before sent him his work entitled "Observations surles Poêtes Italiens"; has been ill since then and unable to work; applies to him as a patron of literature, for pecuniary assistance.
  - Appendix, 1782 August 9; A.L.S. 3p.; Banks, Sir Joseph. London
    Introducing [Pierre Marie Auguste] Broussonet. Has never entered the doors of the House of Commons; congratulates himself on escaping many weary hours. Hopes for peace on such terms as will be advantageous to both parties.
  - Appendix, 1782 August 9; A.L.S. 6p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Concerning the negotiations for peace. Importance of the fisheries. Spanish claims. Transmitting money for salaries of Franklin, Jay, Adams, Carmichael, Dana and Dumas.
    (In triplicate; partly in cipher.)
    Printed in Diplom. Corress. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, V, 652.
  - Appendix, 1782 August 10; A.L.S. 4p.; Destouches, -----. Dunkirk
    Asking that Capt. Bennet Negus be released from Mill Prison and given the command of the "Franklin."
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 August 11; A.L.S. 1p.; Bland, Theodorick. Philadelphia
    At the request of James Hunter, begs him to deliver the enclosed letter to Mrs. [Isabella] Strange.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 August 12; A.L.S. 5p.; Lomagne-Tarride, vicomte de. Bereux
    Account of his five campaigns in America, his capture by the English and his subsequent shipwreck; desires a loan of money and a position in the French army.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 August 17; L.S. 2p.; Puchelberg, -----. Versailles
    Informed by M. [John D.] Schweighauser that his account against the "Alliance" has been allowed by Congress; desires to know when it will be paid.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 August 17; A.L.S. 1p.; Shuttleworth, John. Paris
    His servant will wait for the promised papers, and for any letters Franklin may commit to his care.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 August 26; A.L.S. 3p.; De Ferrière, -----. L'Orient
    Concerning the capture of a vessel, containing his household goods, first by the English and then by the French; only able to reclaim his goods after paying an exhorbitant sum; appeals to Dr. Franklin for redress.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 2; A.L.S. 1p.; Charles Grant, Vicomte de Vaux
    Complains bitterly of receiving no reply to his petition; asks for an interview; lost a fortune supporting the American cause.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 3; D. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Resolution to give the ship "America" to the King of France to replace the "Magnifique," lost in the harbor of Boston.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 5; L.S. 3p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Censuring all the American Agents for their remissness in writing. Possible evacuation of Charleston. Loss of the French ship, "Magnifique." Matters to be remembered when negotiating peace with Great Britain. Loan from France necessary.
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, V. 696.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 6; L.S. 1p.; Lenoir, Jean-Charles-Pierre. Paris
    Enclosing passports for Mr. Harford and his son, for London, and for Mr. Hill, for Spain.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 6; A.L.S. 1p.; Mesny, -----. Paris
    Concerning Dr. Franklin's promise to pay for one hundred copies of M. de la Faye's work, after they should have been sold in America; begs for information of their sale.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 9; D.S. Cha[rle]s Thomson, Sec[retar]y. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Resolve not to issue any more interest bills.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 10; A.L.S. 3p.; Lamarque, Fabre and Co. Paris
    M. [Alexander] Gillon's departure for America, without repaying the money advanced him by their firm; this omission has seriously embarrassed them; apply to Dr. Franklin for assistance.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 10; A.L.S. 2p.; Lamarque, Fabre and Co. Paris
    Transmitting a statement of their receipts and disbursements on account of the United States. Copy of a letter [1p.] from Commodore [Alexander] Gillon relative to the payment of their debt by South Carolina.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 12; L.S. 2p.; La Veuve Dubois and Mesdames Laneorlon. L'Orient
    Money due them for supplies furnished the officers and seamen of the "Bon Homme Richard," the "Pallas" and the "Alliance"; ask him to see that the bill is paid.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 13; A.L.S. 4p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Safe arrival of two vessels from Holland bringing the goods left by Commodore [Alexander] Gillon. Desperate need of money. Mr. [Thomas] Paine's work addressed to Abbé Raynal. Resolutions of Congress.
    (In quadruplicate. Duplicate copy has a postscript.)
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, V, 726.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 14; S. Cha[rle]s Thomson, Sec[retar]y. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Resolutions concerning the proposal loan.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 16; A.L.S. 1p.; Leroy, Alphonse. Paris
    Begging him to forward a letter to Boston.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 17; A.L.S. 2p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
    Announcing the birth of a seven months' daughter—a new American citizen; likens this premature delivery to the premature outbreak of the Revolution; thinks of naming the child Virginia.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 18; L.S. 2p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Refusal of Congress to accept Mr. [Henry] Laurens's resignation; alterations made in Dr. Franklin's powers. Need of money.
    (In quadruplicate; partly in cipher.)
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, V, 743.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1781 November 27; 1782 September 23; D.S. Cha[rle]s Thomson, Sec[retar]y. 1p.; The Continental Congress
    Resolutions concerning Mr. [Robert] Morris's powers as Superintendent of Finance.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 September 14, 23; D.S. Cha[rle]s Thomson, Sec[retar]y. 1p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Resolves relative to proposed European loans.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 24; A.L.S. Besa Woodward, Secretary. 4p.; The University of Dartmouth
    Introducing Mr. John Wheelock, President of the University, and Mr. James Wheelock, and begging him to further the cause of their trip to Europe.
  - Appendix, 1782 September 29; A.L.S. 1p.; Marcel, -----
    Application for work by a surgeon, who had been made prisoner and thereby lost everything.
  - Appendix, 1782 October 2; L.S. 3p.; frères, Rolland. Marseilles
    Concerning the arrival of an American vessel with a cargo of tobacco; their efforts to obtain a good sale for it. Possible that their large woolen manufactory in Languedoc may furnish some goods useful to the Americans.
  - Appendix, 1782 October 5; A.L.S. 1p.; Vicq d' Azyr, Félix
    Introducing Mr. Laurent Josselin, who wishes to go to America.
  - Appendix, 1782 October 6; A.L.S. 2p.; Mecom, Mrs. Jane. Warwick, R.I
    Has not heard from him for two years and a half; sorry if the politeness of the French ladies has lessened his old American acquaintances in his esteem. Death of her granddaughter; other family news.
  - Appendix, 1782 October 9; L.S. 1p.; Williams, Moore and Co. L'Orient
    Arrival of the American vessel "Cicero" with two prizes; thirty French prisoners on one of the prizes set free without an order from Dr. Franklin.
  - Appendix, 1782 October 11; A.L.S. 3p.; Coulougnac, -----. Paris
    Desiring a letter of recommendation to the Governor of Virginia, that he may obtain his assistance in collecting a debt.
  - Appendix, 1782 October 12; A.L.S. 3p.; Lerouge, Camusar et C. Troyes
    Desiring to know the commercial standing of Jean André Stockolm, recently established in Nantes, and reported to be known to him.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 October 12; A.L.S. 1p.; De Castella, -------
    Requesting a private interview and asking that his name be kept secret.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 October 15; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Brantsen, Gerard
    Sending a letter from Prof. Ingen Housz, and offering to deliver the reply.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 October 21; L.S. 2p.; Soulavie, L'Abbé Jean Louis Giraud. Paris
    Acknowledging the "Observations" which will appear in his next volume. Desires Dr. Franklin to recommend him for the vacancy in the Académie des Sciences.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 October 21; L.S. 1p.; Williams, Moore and Co. L'Orient
    Transmitting a receipt from the Commandant of I'Orient for prisoners of war delivered to him.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 October 23; A.L.S. 2p.; Camusar and C. Lerouge. Troyes
    Desiring his opinion as to the amount of credit that can safely be accorded to Mr. [Jean André] Stockolm.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 October 26; A.L.S. 2p.; John Davies and David Gavin. Bordeaux
    Were private passengers on board an English ship; captured and brought to a French prison; wish either to be released or exchanged; have with them an orphan child of three years, George Lewis, whose father died in prison.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 November 1; A.L.S. 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Mrs. Williams not well enough for him to leave at once for Passy; hopes to see Dr. Franklin in a few days.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 November 6; A.L.S. 1p.; Bayard, -----
    Requesting his signature to a claim against the State of Georgia.
  - Appendix, 1782 November 9; L.S. 5p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    America's European policy. Concerning the exchange of prisoners. Affair of Mr. [Henry] Laurens. Execution of [Captain] Huddy [of New Jersey]; retaliation only prevented by the interference of their Majesties. Election of Mr. [Elias] Boudinot [as President of the Congress].
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev. Wharton, V, 871.
  - Appendix, 1782 November 11; A.L.S. 2p.; Morris, Lewis R. Officer for Foreign Affairs
    Sends Dr. Franklin's salary; desires to know what allowance he made his private Secretary.
  - Appendix, 1782 November 15; A.L.S. 1p.; Arendt, Baron d'
    Concerning his claims on Mr. Robert Morris; asks that they may be paid to the Prussian Minister at Paris.
  - Appendix, 1782 November 15; A.L.S. 1p.; frères, Destouches. Roubaix
    Enclosing a letter to be forwarded to Mr. [Matthew] Ridley of Baltimore; sends sample; of goods and request at recommendation.
  - Appendix, 1782 November 19; L. in 3d P. 1p.; d'Escagnac, Baron. Paris
    Obliged, owing to illness, to decline his invitation to dinner.
  - Appendix, 1782 November 21; L.S. 4p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Mr. [Thomas] Jefferson added to the Peace Commission; England's attitude towards peace Necessity of retaining the logwood trade in Jamaica. Mr. Joel Batlow proposes having his own poems printed.
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton,VI, 66.
  - Appendix, 1782 November 27; L.S. 2p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Concerning the relations of Lamarque and Fabre with Mr. [Alexander] Gillon. Opportunity for Dr. Franklins grandson to open a correspondence with the Office of Finance.
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, VI, 85.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 November 29; A.L.S. 1p.; Valmont de Bomare, Jacques-Christophe
    Regrets having been prevented from calling during Dr. Franklin's recent illness; begs him to be present at the opening lecture of his course.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 December 3; A.L. 1p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    The British on the point of leaving Charleston, and the French troops soon to embark.
    (In cipher; in triplicate.)
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, VI, 102.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 December 10; L.S. 3p.; Lanoix, L. Bordeaux
    Offers to give one half the capacity of his ship, for the transportation of goods to America. Asks for a passport and letters to American commercial houses.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 December 14; A.L.S. 2p.; Thun, Ulrich, baron de. Paris
    Concerning the payment of a sum of money of Richard Bache by Mr. [Christian] Schneider of Germantown; appeal of Mr. Auer to have this sum transmitted to the widow Hoeckl[er]in in Ebingen.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 December 14; A.L.S. 2p.; Pierre, -----. Paris
    Recommending M. Saudot to Dr. Franklin's generosity.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 December 18; A.L.S. 2p.; de Bellehache, Parent. Paris
    Reminds him of his friendship for the writer's father, and asks for aid.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1782 December 21; L.S. 1p.; Penet, P
    Regrets that his creditors have been annoying Dr. Franklin; has assured them that Dr. Franklin has nothing to do with his engagements.
  - Appendix, 1782 December 27; A.L.S. 4p.; Barclay, David. Youngsbury
    Dr. [John] Fothergill's biography being written by Dr. [John Coakley] Lettsom, a physician of London; desires his advice as to inserting in the work, the paper entitled "Basis of a Plan of Reconciliation, etc." Religions scruples of Friends in Pennsylvania.
  - Appendix, 1782 December 28; L.S. 1p.; Enore, -----. Paris
    Concerning the payment of certain bills.
  - Appendix, 1782 December 30; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Laurens, Henry. Paris
    Inviting Dr. Franklin to dine with him on January 2d.
  - Appendix, 1782 December 31; L. 2p.; Huntington, Samuel
    Instructions for negotiating peace.
    (In untranslated cipher.)
  - Appendix, 1782; A.L.S. 1p.; Favier, -----
    Begs for a written statement which will give the lie to the calumnies against him circulated by his enemies.
  - Appendix, 1782; A. Mem. 1p.; Grand ?, Ferdinand
    If England's offer of peace is refused, means of continuing the war must be found; a fleet is needed, impossible for America to build one; France must do nothing which is not to her true interest; the approaching campaign would require twenty-four millions of French money. Terrible consequences of a union of the savages with the English.
    A.E. by Dr. Franklin. "M. Grand. Points for conversation."
  - Appendix, [1782.]; L.S. 3p.; de Loose, Jean Baptiste. Ghent, Flanders
    His intention to ship supplies to America; desires letters which will give him free access to certain American ports.
  - Appendix, 1782; L.S. 1p.; Williams, Moore and Co.
    Enclosing papers relative to the capture of a prize-ship by an American vessel.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, L. in 3d P. 4p.; de Thurn, -----. Metz
    Comes of an old and respectable family in Alsace; his trade as vintner; has decided to emigrate with his only child to America; encloses a project for trading in wine which will enrich any American firm.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 January1; A.L.S. 3p.; Bache, Sarah. Philadelphia
    Recounting in detail the doings of the little Baches.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 January 2; L.S. 3p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Departure of the French army. [Thomas] Jefferson about to sail for France. Encloses Resolutions of Congress; finances still in great distress.
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, VI, 192.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 January 3; A.L.S. 1p.; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste
    Introducing a man from Dunkirk and congratulating him on the bright prospect for America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 January 4; A.L.S. 1p.; Dutartre, Madame Melin
    Begs him not to forget her in 1783, as he did in 1782; prevented seeing him in Passy owing to his being engaged at the time; urges him to dine with her.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 January 6; L.S. 7p.; Livingston, Robert R. Philadelphia
    Mr. [Thomas] Barclay's objection to the Convention relative to Consuls. Question of a further French loan, and of restoring confiscated property. Importance of retaining the fisheries. Question of salaries. Important happenings in America.
    Printed in Diplom. Corresp. of the Am. Rev., Wharton, VI, 198.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 January 29; A.L.S. 1p.; Johonnot, Samuel Cooper. Geneva
    Thanking him for past favors and congratulating him upon the conclusion of peace.
  - Appendix, 1783 July 28; A.L.S.J.F. Cigna [Secretary]. 2p.; The Academy of Sciences of Turin. Turin
    Inviting him to become an honorary member of their Society.
  - Appendix, 1783 August 25; A.L.S. 3p.; Banks, Sir Joseph. London
    Sorry that his copy of the Transactions of the Royal Society has been delayed; the Society anxious to hear of the balloon experiments of M. [Joseph Michel] Montgolfier and his competitor. Gen. Washington compared to Cincinnatus. Hopes that Dr. Franklin can soon leave politics for philosophy.
  - Appendix, 1783 August; Printed N. 1p.; Mme. d'Enneville, Comtesse de Choiseul and M. du Buc
    Announcing the marriage of M. du Buc-Saint-Olympe and Mme. De Longpré.
  - Appendix, 1783 September 29; L.S. 2p.; Grand, Ferdinand
    Acknowledging a sum of money to be placed to Dr. Franklin's credit.
    (In parallel, French and English.)
  - Appendix, 1783 October 1; A.L.S. 2p.; de Robespierre, Maximilian-Marie Isidore. Arras
    His successful plea for the repeal of a sentence abolishing lightning rods; his speech upon that occasion printed; sends a copy to the illustrious inventor of the lightning rod.
  - Appendix, 1783 October 3; A.L.S. 2p.; De Blaugy, Ducarne. Hirson
    Incensed at Dr. Franklin daring to call his balloon an infant just coming to birth; certain that if the balloon had been invented earlier, Gibraltar would have been taken; several trips made from Calais to Dover.
  - Appendix, 1783 Ocotber 7; A.L.S. 10p.; De Blaugy, Ducarne. Hirson
    Experiments in aerial navigation; practical value of balloons; questions of height and distance. Observations on bees.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 October 10; A.L.S. 3p.; Saussure, Horace Bénédict de
    Acknowledging a copy of the Constitutions of the United States. Sends essay on hygrometry. Landriani, Professor of Physics of Milan, deputed by the Austrian Government to have lightning rods erected on all public buildings in Austrain Lombardy; also to write such an essay as shall show the people the utility of the rods; desires data as to the use of lightning rods in America.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 October 19; A.L.S. 5p.; Deane, Silas. London
    Defends himself against the charges of intimacy with Benedict Arnold, and of furnishing Lord Sheffield with most of the facts and principles in his recent work on the Commerce [of the United States].
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 November 7; A.L.S. 3p.; Banks, Sir Joseph. London
    At a meeting of the Royal Society, he read Dr. Franklin's two recent letters on balloon experiments in Paris; the Society hailed with delight his return to philosophical pursuits; desires to know whether he would choose to have these letters printed in the Philosophical Transactions.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 November 7; A.L.S. 2p.; Deane, Silas. London
    Endeavoring to get the restrictions on American trade with the West Indies modified or removed. Has written long letters to Mr. [Thomas] Barclay and to Col. [Jeremiah] Wadsworth concerning the settlement of his accounts.
    Printed in Collections of New York Historical Society, 1890. Deane Papers, V, 232.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 November 19; D.S. 3p.; de Thurn, -----. Fontainebleau
    His appointment by the King of France, as Secret Agent in England.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1783 December 7; L.S. 3p.; Perkins, William Lee. Kingston-upon-Thames
    The diploma electing his father a corresponding member of the Royal Society of Medicine at Paris, arrived after his decease; hopes that this honor may be transferred to him. Enclosing a printed treatise, in Latin, on Influenza [16p.]
  - Appendix, 1783; 1p.; -----, -----
    Poem addressed to Dr Franklin on the occasion of his receiving from the Comtesse de Deux-Ponts, a bâton of thorn-wood, surmounted by an apple of gold and representing a liberty-cap.
    (In French. Printed vy Didot l'ainé.)
  - Appendix, A.L.S. 2p.; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste
    Read with great pleasure Franklin's hypothesis concerning the extraordinary motions of the earth; comments thereon.
  - Appendix, A.L.S. 1p.; de Savagnac, Baron. Paris
    Preparing for publication a list of the Ministers and Ambassadors of all Nations; desires a complete list of those accredited by the United States.
  - Appendix, 1784 January 13; L.S. 2p.; Lafreté, Jean-Jacques de. Paris
    Has scarcely ventured out since his great bereavement but will come to Passy for a few days; desires a recommendation for M. Philippe Aribert, who wishes the American Consulship in Languedoc.
  - Appendix, 1783 January; to 1784 January; 90p.; Finck, Jacques
    Account of Dr. Franklin's family expenses. 1 vol. 410.
  - Appendix, 1784 March 23; A.L.S. 4p.; Banks, Sir Joseph. London
    Movements of meteors Dr. [Sir Charles] Blagden's general thoughts thereon. [Sir William] Herschel's observations on the planet Mars. Dearth of aerostatic experiments. A history of the construction of Ed[dy] (i)stone Lighthouse soon to be published.
  - Appendix, 1784 March 30; L.S. 3p.; De Maire, Jacques. Paris
    Account of his twenty-eight years of military service in France and America; desires Dr. Franklin's assistance in obtaining a position in the Island of San Domingo.
    A.E. recommending M Le Maire warmly. S. B[enjamin] Franklin.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 May 6; A.L.S. 1p.; Washington, General George. Philadelphia
    Introducing Mr. [Nathaniel] Tracy of Massachusetts Bay.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 May 28; 1p.; Chaumont, Jacques-Donatien Le Ray de
    Bill for house rent. S. Le Ray de Chaumont, B[enjamin] Franklin and Tho[ma]s Barclay.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 July 1; A.L.S. 2p.; De Menusiglio, Joseph Ange Comte De Saluces. Turin
    Application of keys to the harmonica, by the Abbé Perno Piémontois; desires information on this point. The Academy soon to publish the first volume of its new works; begs Dr. Franklin to contribute.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 August 2; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Jones, Capt. John Paul. Paris
    Accepting his invitation to dinner on August 4th.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 August 13; A.L.S. 4p.; Banks, Sir Joseph. London
    Presenting him with the gold medal struck by the Royal Society in honor of Capt. [James] Cook; acknowledging his gracious reception of Capt. Cook's Voyage, which was sent him by the King's direction. Experiments with balloons in England.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 August 19; Mem. S. 1p.; Angenend, ------. Paris
    Receipted tailor's bill.
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 [August.]; Printed N. 1p.; M. le Curé and Madame Le Veillard. Passy
    A notification of a meeting at which a collection for the poor will be taken.
    (In French and Latin.)
  - to Benjamin Franklin, 1784 November 17; A.L.S. 2p.; Perkins, William Lee. Kingston